Shima Adnanbasmeni

Location: Hartlepool, UK | Telephone: +44 (0) 7471212289 |

Email: shima.adnanbasmenj@gmail.com Github: https://github.com/Shimaadnan

Professional Profile

Mathematics postgraduate and full-stack developer with 10 years of experience in teaching. Recently graduated from Code Your Future, a rigorous 9 month software development program. A focus on active listening and providing constructive feedback, as ex-teachers like to do. Keen interest in Digital, Data, and Technology.

Skills

Technical: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Git, Github, VSCode, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, Pair Programming, Project Management (Miro, Trello, KanBan etc).

Experience

Mar 2022 - Apr 2023 Code Your Future, Manchester

Full-Stack Developer - https://github.com/khmdagal/The-Collective-Foundation

- Shipped a full stack CMS product to an international client in collaboration with a team of three developers in an Agile team
- Built complete custom CMS application for NGO team who helps protect environment from various pollution
- Delivered application with interactive features using React, Node, and PostgreSQL database integration on the backend in just 4 weeks

Dec 2022 – Language Empire, Manchester

Freelance Interpreter

- Provided professional spoken and written interpretation services to a diverse range of public sector clients in individual or family appointments
- Worked closely with people from 3 different countries facilitation, interpreting between parties in real time
- Documented and communicated in text and spoken word between multiple stakeholders

Jun 2017 - Feb 2022 Mahabad, Iran

Mathematics Tutor

- Instructed Mathematics and Engineering students in Calculus I & II and Differential Equations
- Supported 20 first and second-year university students to achieve first-class grades in each term
- Explored and developed new pedagogical approaches to teaching mathematics

Sep 2012 – Feb 2017 Soran University, Soran, Erbil, Iraq

Mathematics Lecturer & Translator

- Taught Applied Mathematics to 3 group of 30 engineering students over 5 years, including Advanced Calculus, Engineering Mathematics, and Differential Equations
- Translated 2 advanced mathematics courses from English to Kurdish
- Supervised 3 final-year students during their BSC project execution

Education & Qualifications

Mar 2022 – Apr 2023 Code Your Future, Manchester Full-Stack Developer

• Completed a nine-month course in software development focusing on web development, Agile, and product thinking

Sep 2021 – Feb 2022 Learning and Skills Services, Stockton-on-Tees Community Interpreter

• Completed a six-month course encompassing various services in the UK and relevant linguistic models for non-English speakers in the UK.

Sep 2010 – Jan 2022 Urmia University, Urmia, Iran Master of Mathematics

• Pure Mathematics, Functional Analysis, C* Algebras

Languages

- Persian Native
- Kurdish Native
- English C1
- Turkish Native